as part of MIT course success zero nine
作为麻省理工学院课程成功的一部分， 零九
nine on artificial general intelligence
人工智能 九
I got a chance to sit down with
我有机会 坐下来
Christophe Coe
Christophe Coe
who's one of the seminal figures in
谁是其中的开创性人物 之一
neurobiology in neuroscience and
神经科学和神经科学中的神经生物学
generally in the study of consciousness
一般在意识研究中
he is the president the chief scientific
他是 首席科学家
officer of the Allen Institute for brain
艾伦 研究所大脑的官员
science in Seattle from 1986 to 2013 he
从1986年到2013年他在西雅图的科学
was the professor at Caltech before that
在此 之前 是 加州理工学院 的 教授
he was at MIT he is extremely well sited
他在麻省理工学院， 他的 选址 非常好
over a hundred thousand citations his
超过十万次引用他的
research his writing his ideas have had
研究他的写作他的想法
big impact on the scientific community
对科学界产生重大影响
and the general public in the way we
而 在这样 的普通市民 ，我们
think about consciousness in the way we
以我们的方式思考意识
see ourselves as human beings he's the
把自己视为人类， 他就是这样
author of several books the quest for
几 本书追求作者
consciousness and your biological
意识和你的生物学
approach and a more recent book
方法和最近的 一本书
consciousness confessions of a romantic
一种浪漫的意识忏悔
reductionist if you enjoy this
还原者， 如果你 喜欢这个
conversation this course subscribe click
对话本课程订阅点击
the little bell I got to make sure you
小 铃铛我要 确保你
never miss a video and in the comments
永远不会错过视频和评论
leave suggestions for any people you'd
为你的任何人 留下 建议
like to see be part of the course or any
喜欢看到成为课程的一部分或任何
ideas that you would like us to explore
想法 ， 你想 我们去 探索
thanks very much I hope you enjoy okay
非常感谢我希望你喜欢 没事
before we delve into the beautiful
在我们钻研美丽之前
mysteries of consciousness let's zoom
意识的奥秘让我们放大
out a little bit and let me ask do you
出来一点点 ，让我 问你
think there's intelligent life out there
认为那里有聪明的 生活
in the universe yes I do believe so we
在宇宙中是的，我相信 ， 所以 我们
have no evidence of it but I think the
没有证据，但我认为
probabilities are overwhelming in favor
概率是压倒性的
of it
它
give me a universe where we have 10 to
给我一个我们有10到的宇宙
the 11 galaxies and each galaxy is
11个星系和每个星系都是
between 10 to the 11 10 to the 12 stars
从10 到11 10到12星
and we know more stars have one or more
我们知道 更多的明星有一个或多个
planets so how does that make you feel
行星那么， 如何 让你感觉
it still makes me feel special because I
它仍然让我觉得特别，因为我
have experiences I feel the world I
有经验，我觉得世界上我
experience the world and independent of
体验世界，独立于
whether there are other creatures out
是否有其他生物出来
there I still feel the world and I have
还有 我还是觉得世界，我有
access to this world in this very
在这方面 进入 这个世界
strange compelling way and that's the
奇怪的引人注目的方式，这就是
core of human existence now he said
他说，现在 是人类生存的核心
human do you think if those intelligent
人类你认为如果那些聪明
creatures are out there do you think
你觉得那里有生物吗？
they experience
他们经历过
their world yes they evolved if they are
他们的世界 是的，如果他们是进化的话
product of natural evolution if it would
如果愿意 ，自然 进化的 产物
have to be they will also experience
必须是他们也将体验
their own world so consciousness isn't
他们自己的世界所以意识不是
just a human your ID it's it's much
只是一个人类你的身份证就是它
wider it's probably it may be spread
更广泛的可能它可能会传播
across all of biology we have the only
在所有生物学中 我们都是唯一的
thing that we have special is we can
我们有特殊的东西是我们可以
talk about it of course not all people
谈论它当然 不是所有人
can talk about the babies and little
可以 谈论 婴儿和小
children can talk about the patients who
孩子们可以谈论 患者
have have a Stoke and let's see the left
有一个 斯托克 ，让我们看到左边
inferior frontal gyrus can talk about it
下额回可以谈论它
but most normal adult people can talk
但 大多数正常的成年人都 可以说话
about it and so we think that makes us
关于它，所以我们认为 这使我们
special compared to little monkeys a
特别是与 小猴子 相比 a
dogs or cats or mice or all the other
狗 或猫或老鼠或所有其他
creatures that we share the planet with
我们与 地球 共享的生物
but all the evidence seems to suggest
但所有证据似乎都表明了这一点
that they to experience the world and so
他们要体验世界等等
it's overwhelmingly likely that other
其他人绝对有可能
alien that aliens would also experience
外星人也会经历的外星人
their world of course differently
他们的世界当然不同
because they have a difference in serum
因为他们的血清有差异
they've different sense of they had a
他们已经不同意义的，他们有一个
very different environment but the fact
环境 非常 不同， 但事实
that I would strongly suppose that they
我强烈认为他们
also have experiences if your pain and
也有经验， 如果你的痛苦和
pleasure and see in some sort of
快乐， 并在某种程度上看到
spectrum and here and have all the other
频谱和这里，并拥有所有其他
sensors of course their language if they
传感器 当然是他们的语言，如果他们
have one would be different so we might
有一个是不同的 所以我们可能会
not be able to understand their poetry
不 能够理解他们的诗歌
about the experiences that they have
关于他们 有 经验
that's correct right so in a talk in a
这是正确的， 所以在一个谈话中
video I've heard you mention support so
视频我听说你提到支持了
a DAC sound that you came up with
你提出的DAC声音
there you go up with as part of your
在那里，你作为你的一部分
family when you were young first of all
你年轻时的家庭
you're a technically a Midwestern boy
你是技术上的中西部男孩
you just secondly yes after that you
你只是在那之后是你
traveled around a bit and it's a little
走了一会儿，这有点儿
bit of the accent you talked about
你谈到的一点口音
support so the DAC solid having these
因此DAC支持这些
elements of humaneness of consciousness
意识人性的要素
that he discovered so I just wanted to
他发现了所以我只是想
ask can you look back and you childhood
问你可以 回顾一下 你的童年吗？
and remember one was the first time you
记得有一个是你第一次
realized you yourself sort of from a
从某种意识到你自己
third-person perspective or our
第三人称视角或我们的
conscious being this idea of you know
意识到你知道这个想法
stepping outside yourself and seeing
踩到外面看看
well there's something special going on
那里有一些特别的东西
here in my brain I can't really actually
在我的大脑里， 我实际上并不是真的
it's a good question I'm not sure I
这是一个很好的问题，我不知道 我
recall a discrete moment I mean you take
回忆起我所说的 离散时刻
it for granted because that's the only
这是理所当然的，因为那是唯一的
world you know
你知道的世界
at the only world I know you know it's a
在唯一的 世界， 我知道你知道它是一个
world of seeing and hearing voices and
视听声音的世界，
touching and all the other things so
触摸和 其他 所有 的东西 ，所以
it's only much later at early in my
它只是在我早期的早些时候
undergrad days when I became when I
大学时代，当我成为我的时候
enrolled in physics and in philosophy
报名参加物理和 哲学
that I really thought about it and
我真的以为这件事 和
thought well this is really
好想，这是真的
fundamentally very very mysterious and
从根本上说非常神秘
there's nothing really in physics right
在物理学中没有什么是正确的
now that explains his transition from
现在解释了他 从 过渡
the physics of the brain to feelings
大脑对物理的感受
where do the feelings come in all right
哪里进来 没事 的感情
so you can look at the foundational
所以你可以 看一下 基础
equation of quantum mechanics general
量子力学方程
relativity you can look at the period
相对论你可以看看这个时期
table of the elements you can look at
您可以查看的元素表
the endless 80g seat chat and our genes
无休止的80g 座位聊天和我们的 基因
and no way is consciousness yet I wake
我醒来时没有意识
up every morning to a world where I have
每天早上 到我所拥有的世界
experiences and so that's the hub of the
经验，所以这是的中心
ancient mind-body problem how do
古代的身心问题怎么办
experiences get into the world so what
经历进入世界所以
is consciousness experience
是意识体验
consciousness is any any conte any
意识是任何任何 任何 康特
experience some people call it
有人称之为体验
subjective feeling some people call it
有些人称之为主观感受
phenomenon phenomenology some people
现象现象学有些人
call it quality of their philosophy all
称之为他们的哲学品质
denote the same thing it feels like
表示同样的感觉
something in the famous word of as if a
在着名的词中的东西，如同一个
loss at Thomas Nagel it feels like
在Thomas Nagel失去了感觉
something to be a bad or to be a you
一些不好或成为你的东西
know an American out to be angry or to
知道一个美国人 会 生气或者生气
be sad or to be in love or to have pain
要难过，要恋爱或有痛苦
and that is what experience is any
这就是经验
possible experience could be as mundane
可能的经历可能是 平凡的
as just sitting in a chair could be as
刚刚坐在椅子 可以像
exalted as you know having a mystical
因为你知道有一个神秘的崇拜
moment you know in in deep meditation
你在深度冥想中知道的 那一刻
those are just different forms of
那些只是不同的形式
experiences experience so if you were to
如果你愿意，体验经验
sit down with maybe the next skip a
坐下来也许下一个跳过a
couple generations of IBM Watson
几代IBM Watson
something that one jeopardy
一个危险的东西
what is the gap I guess the question is
我猜这个问题是什么差距
between Watson that might be much more
沃森之间可能会更多
smarter than you then ask then all any
比你聪明， 然后 问任何所有
human alive but may not have experience
人活着，但可能没有 经验
what is the gap well so that's a big big
什么是差距很大，所以这是一个很大的
question that's occupied people for the
那个占据了人们的问题
last certainly last 50 years since we
最后肯定是我们的50年
you know since he happened the birth of
你知道自从他出生以来
of computers that's a question on
电脑这是一个问题
chilling try to answer and of course he
寒意试着回答， 当然还有 他
did it in this indirect way by proposing
通过提议以这种间接的方式做到了
its test and operational test so but
它的 测试和操作 测试，但是
that's not really that's you know he
那不是你真正知道他的
tried to get it what does it mean for
试图得到它意味着什么
person to think and then he had this
有人思考，然后他有这个
test like you lock him away and then you
测试就像你把他锁起来然后你
have a communication with him and then
然后和他沟通
you try to to guess after while whether
你试图猜测 是否
that is a person or whether it's a
这是一个人还是一个人
computer system there's no question that
计算机系统毫无疑问
now or very soon
现在 或很快
you know Alexa or Siri or you know
你知道Alexa还是Siri或者你知道
Google now will pass this test right and
谷歌现在将通过这项测试的权利 和
you can game it but you know ultimately
你可以游戏，但最终你知道
certainly in your generation
肯定在你这一代
there will be machines that will speak
会有会说话的机器
with complete poise that will remember
完全平衡， 将记住
everything you ever said they'll
你曾经说过的一切
remember every email you ever had like
记住你曾经喜欢的每封电子邮件
like Samantha remember in the movie her
像萨曼莎在电影里记得她
yeah it's no question it's gonna happen
是的，毫无疑问 它 会发生
but of course the key questions is does
但当然 ，关键 的问题是 不
it feel like anything to be Samantha in
感觉就像 什么是 萨曼莎
a movie home too does it feel like
它也是 一个电影之 家
anything to be Watson and there one has
什么都是 沃森，有一个
to be very very strongly think they're
非常强烈地认为他们是
two different concepts here that we call
我们称之为两个不同的概念
mingle there is the concept of
乐居有概念
intelligence natural or artificial and
智力 自然或人工和
there is a concept of consciousness of
有一种意识的概念
experience natural or artificial those
体验自然或人工的那些
are very very different things now
现在是非常不同的事情
historically we associate consciousness
在历史上我们联想到意识
with intelligence why because we live in
有智慧的原因，因为我们生活在
a world
一个世界
leaving aside computers of natural
抛开自然电脑
selection where we are surrounded by
选择我们被 包围的地方
creatures either our own kin that are
生物无论是我们 自己 的 亲人是
less or more intelligent or we go across
更少或更聪明或我们经历过
species some some are more adapted to
物种有些 更适应
particular environment others are less a
特别的环境， 其他人则少
tablet whether it's a whale or dog or
平板电脑无论是鲸鱼还是狗鲸鱼
you go talk about a Paramecium or a
你去谈论一个 草履虫或一个
little worm alright and and we see the
小蠕虫好了，我们看到了
complexity of the nervous system goes
神经系统的复杂性变
from one cell to two specialized cells
从一个细胞 到两个特化细胞
to a worm that has three net that has
一个有三个网的蠕虫
30% of its cells and nerve cells to
其细胞和神经细胞的 30％
creature like also like a blue whale
像蓝鲸一样的生物
that ever has had a billion even more
曾经有过十亿 甚至更多
nerve cells and so they based on
他们基于神经细胞等
behavioral evidence and based on the
行为证据和基于
underlying neuroscience we believe that
潜在的神经科学我们相信
as these creatures become more complex
因为这些生物变得更加复杂
they are better adapted to it to their
他们更适应他们的
particular ecological niche and they
特别是生态位和它们
become more conscious probably because
变得更有意识可能是因为
their brain calls and we believe
他们的大脑呼唤，我们相信
consciousness unlike the ancient ancient
意识不同于古代古代
people thought most almost every cult
人们认为 几乎每一个邪教组织
thought that consciousness with
认为与意识
intelligence has to do with your heart
智慧与你的心灵有关
mm-hmm and you still to see that today
mm-hmm，今天你仍然可以看到它
you see honey I love you is on my house
你看到我爱你的亲爱的就在我的家里
yes but what you should actually say no
是的，但你应该说不
honey I love you was all my lateral
亲爱的，我爱你是我所有的横向
hypothalamus and for Valentine's Day you
下丘脑 和情人节 你
should give you a sweetheart
应该给你一个 甜心
you know hypothalamic same piece of
你知道下丘脑同一块
chocolate another heart shaped chocolate
巧克力另一种 心形巧克力
right and you know so we still have this
对，你知道我们仍然有这个
language but now we believe it's a brain
语言，但现在我们认为这是一个大脑
and so we see brains of different
所以我们看到了不同的大脑
complexity and we think well they have
复杂性，我们认为他们有
different levels of consciousness
不同 的意识 水平
they're capable of different experiences
他们有不同的经历
[Music]
[音乐]
but now we confront a world where we
但现在我们不得不面对 一个世界 里，我们
know where we're beginning to engineer
知道我们开始设计的地方
intelligence and it's radical unclear
情报和它的根本不清楚
whether the intelligence we're
我们是否有智慧
engineering has anything to do with
工程与任何有关
consciousness and whether it can
意识以及 是否 可以
experience anything because
体验一切， 因为
fundamentally what's the difference
从根本上说有什么区别
intelligence is about function
智力是关于功能的
intelligence no matter exactly how you
智慧无论你究竟如何
define it sort of an adaptation to new
定义它适应新的
environments being able to learn and
环境 能够 学习和
quickly understand you know you know the
很快就明白你知道你知道的
setup of this and what's going on and
这个设置和正在发生的事情和
who the actors and what's gonna happen
谁是演员，又会发生什么
next
下一个
gets all about function consciousness is
得到关于功能意识的一切
not about function consciousness is
不是关于功能意识的
about being it's in some sense much
从某种意义上说它是多少
fundamental you can see folks that you
基本的，你可以看到你的人
can see this in two in several cases you
可以在 两个在几种情况下 看到 你
can see it for instance in the case of
例如，在这种情况下可以看到它
the clinic when you're dealing with
当你处理诊所
patients who are let's say had a stroke
让我们 说有中风的病人
or had were in traffic accident etc
或曾发生 过交通事故 等
they're pretty much in mobile Terri
他们 几乎 都是移动Terri
Schiavo you may have heard historically
你可能在历史上听过Schiavo
she was a person here in the in the 90s
她是 90年代的 一个人
in flora - heart Stood Still she was
在植物群中 - 心脏仍然存在
reanimated and for the next fourteen
复活，接下来的十四岁
years she was what's called in a
多年来， 她就是所谓的
vegetative state so there are thousands
植物人状态所以有成千上万
of people in a vegetative state so
那种处于植物人状态的人
they're you know they're you know
他们你知道他们是你知道的
they're like this occasionally they open
他们偶尔会打开他们
their eyes for two three four five six
他们的目光为两 三四五六
eight hours and then close their eyes
八个小时然后闭上眼睛
they have sleep-wake cycle occasionally
他们偶尔会有睡眠 - 觉醒周期
they have behavior they do you know
他们有你知道的行为
there but there's no way that you can
那里但 你 没有 办法
establish a lawful relationship between
建立合法的关系
what you see or the doctor says or the
你看到的或医生说的或者
mom says and what the patient does
妈妈说， 患者做了 什么
correctly so so the so the there isn't
正确如此， 所以没有
any behavior yet in some of these people
其中一些人的任何行为
there is still experience you can you
还有经验，你可以
can
能够
design and build brain machine
设计和建立脑机
interfaces where you can see there's
接口，你可以看到那里
they still explain something and of
他们还解释什么的和
course at these cases of locked-in state
当然在这些锁定状态的情况下
there's a famous book called that the
有一 本着名的 书叫做
diving bell and the butterfly well yet
潜水钟和 蝴蝶还好
an editor French editor here the stroke
编辑法国编辑在这里 中风
in the in the brainstem unable to move
在脑干中无法移动
except his vertical eyes eye movement he
除了他的垂直眼睛 运动他
could just move his the eyes up and down
可以只移动他的眼睛上下
and he dictated an entire book and some
他指的是一本完整的书 和一些 书
people even lose this at the end it all
人们甚至在最后都失去了这一切
the evidence seems to suggest that
证据似乎暗示了这一点
they're still in there in this case you
在这种情况下，你仍然在那里
have no behavior your consciousness
没有你的意识行为
second cases tonight like all of us
第二个 案子今晚 像 我们所有人一样
you're gonna go to sleep close your eyes
你会睡觉闭上你的眼睛
you go to sleep you will wake up inside
你去睡觉， 你会 在 里面 醒来
your sleeping body and you will have
你的睡眠身体，你会有
conscious experiences they are different
有意识的经历他们是不同的
from everyday experience you might fly
从日常经验中你可能会飞
you might not be surprised that you're
你可能不会感到惊讶，你是
flying you might meet a long-dead pet
飞行你可能会遇到一个 长期死去的 宠物
childhood dog and you're not surprised
童年的狗，你并不感到惊讶
that you're meeting them you know but
你要 会见他们，你知道，但
you have conscious experience of love of
你 有自觉的爱的经历
hate you know they can be very emotional
讨厌你知道他们可以 非常情绪化
your body during this stage typically to
在 这个阶段 你的身体 通常是
them state sends an active signal to
他们状态发送一个有效信号
your motor neurons to paralyze you it's
你的运动神经元使你瘫痪了
called atonia right because if you don't
称为atonia，因为如果你不这样做
have that like some patience what do you
有一点耐心，你有什么用
do you act out your dreams you get
你表现出你的梦想吗？
proximal and behavioral disorder which
近端和行为障碍
is a bad which is bad juju to get okay
是一个 坏是坏朱朱 拿到好
third case is pure experience so I
第三种情况是纯粹的经历所以 我
recently had this what some people call
最近这有些人称之为
a mystical experience I went to
一个神秘的经验， 我去 了
Singapore and went into a flotation tank
新加坡并 进入了 一个 浮选槽
yeah alright so this is a big tub filled
是的， 所以 这是一个盛大的浴缸
was ever with water that's a body
曾经的水是身体
temperature and Epsom salt you still
你 仍然 温度和泻盐
completely naked you lie inside of it
你完全赤身裸体躺在里面
you close the layer Ignace complete
你关闭了 Ignace完成 的图层
darkness soundproof so very quickly you
黑暗隔音这么快你
become body less because you're floating
因为你漂浮而变得更少
and you're naked you have no rings no
而你是赤裸裸的你没有戒指没有
watch no nothing you don't feel your
没有什么你 不觉得你的
body anymore it's no sound soundless
身体再也没声音了
there's no surf if a photon a sightless
如果一个光子是无视的， 那就没有 冲浪了
timeless because after while early on
永恒，因为在早期之后
you actually hear your heart but then
你真的听到了你的心， 但 随后
that you you sort of adapt to that and
你有点适应那个和
then sort of the passage of time ceases
然后排序的时间的流逝 的 停止
yeah and if you train yourself like in a
是的，如果你像一个人一样训练自己
meditation not to swing early on you
冥想不要 早点 摆 在你身上
think aloud you it's a little bit spooky
大声想起你有点怪异
you feel somewhat uncomfortable or you
你觉得有点不舒服 ， 或者 你
think well I'm gonna get bored but
好好想想， 我会觉得无聊但是
which I do not to think actively you
我不会 积极思考你
become mindless so there you are body
变得盲目， 所以你就是身体
less timeless you know sound less
你知道的 声音越少越少
sightless mindless but you're in a
没有头脑的人没有头脑， 但你在一个人
conscious experience you're not asleep
有意识的经历 你 没有睡着
you're not asleep you're you you are
你不是在 睡觉，你就是你
being of pure your pure being there
在那里是纯洁的存在
isn't any function you aren't doing any
不是你没有做的任何功能
computation you're not remembering
计算你不记得了
you're not projecting you're not
你没有预测到你不是
planning yet you're fully conscious
计划但你完全清醒
you're fully conscious there's something
你完全意识到 有什么东西
going out there it could be just a side
走出去它可能 只是一个 方面
effect so what is the the you mean
效果那么 你的意思是 什么
epiphenomenon so what is the salaat
epiphenomenon 所以什么是salaat
effect meaning why what what what what
效果意义为什么 什么是什么
is the function of you being able to lay
是你能够躺下的功能
in this sense sensory free deprivation
在这种意义上， 感官自由剥夺
tank and still have a conscious
坦克仍然有意识
experience
经验
additionally myself obviously we didn't
另外 我自己显然没有
evolve with flotation tanks in our in
随着我们的浮选坦克进化
our environment I mean so biology is not
我的环境 我的意思是生物学不是
totally bad at asking why question to
完全不好 问为什么问题
the nominal question why do we have two
名义上的问题为什么我们有两个
eyes why don't we have four eyes or
眼睛为什么我们没有四只眼睛或者
three eyes or something well no there's
三只眼睛或者其他东西没有
probably a there is a function to that
可能是 有一个功能
but it's we're not very good at
但它是我们不太 擅长
answering those questions we can
回答我们可以提出的问题
speculate endlessly where biology is
无休止地推测生物学在哪里
very or science is very good about
非常或科学非常好
mechanistic question why is that charged
机械问题为什么这是 充电的
in the universe right we find a certain
在宇宙中 我们找到了一定的
universe where there positive negative
宇宙哪里有 积极的消极
charges why why does quantum mechanics
指责为什么量子力学
Hall you know what
大厅 你知道吗
why doesn't some other theory hold
为什么其他理论不成立
quantum mechanics hold in our universe
量子力学在宇宙中占有一席之地
is very unclear why so Tillie nominal
很 不清楚为什么 Tillie名义上
question why questions are difficult to
问为什么问题很难
answer clearly there's some relationship
明确回答有一些关系
between complexity brain processing
复杂性大脑处理之间
power and consciousness but however in
权力和意识， 但在
these cases in these three examples RK I
这三个例子 中的 这些案例是 RK I.
gave one is an everyday experience at
给了一个是日常的体验
night the other one is a young Tom on
晚上另一个是年轻的汤姆
third one it's in principle you can
第三，原则上你可以
everybody can have these sort of
每个人都可以拥有这些
mystical experiences you have a
你有一个神秘的经历
dissociation of function form of
功能形式的分离
intelligence from from conscious no
来自有意识的智力
consciousness you caught me asking a
意识到你抓住我问一个
white question let me ask a question
白问题让我问一个问题
that's not a white question you're
这不是一个白人问题
giving a talk later today on the Turing
今天晚些时候在图灵发表演讲
test for intelligence and consciousness
测试智力和意识
drawing lines between the two so is
两者之间画线也是如此
there a scientific way to say there's
有一种科学的方式可以说有
consciousness present in this entity or
意识存在于这个实体或
not and to anticipate your answer
没有，并期待你的答案
because
因为
you also there's a neurobiological
你 还有神经生物学
answer so we can test a human brain but
回答所以我们可以测试一个人脑 但是
if you take a machine brain that you
如果你把机器大脑拿走了 你
don't know tests for yet how would you
不知道测试你怎么样？
even begin to approach a test if there's
如果有的话，甚至开始接近测试
consciousness present in this thing okay
意识存在于这件事中没关系
that's a really good question so let me
这是一个非常好的 问题， 所以让我吧
take in two steps so as you point out
当你指出时，请分两步
for for for for humans let's just stick
因为对于 人类来说， 让我们坚持下去
with humans there's now a test called
与人类现在有一个叫做的测试
the zap and zip it's a procedure where
zap和 zip这是一个程序
you ping the brain using transcranial
你用经颅扫过大脑
magnetic stimulation you look at the
磁力刺激你看看
electrical reverberations essentially
基本上是电混响
using EEG and then you can measure the
使用脑电图然后你可以测量
complexity of this plain response and
这种 简单反应的 复杂性 和
you can do this in a way people in
你可以通过 人们 的方式做到这一点
asleep normal people you can do it in a
你可以在一个普通人睡着了
wake people and then anesthetize them
叫醒人然后麻醉他们
you can do it in patients and it's it it
你可以在患者身上做到这 一点就是这样
has hundred percent accuracy that in all
有百分之百的准确度 ，在所有
those cases when you're clear the
那些你清楚的情况
patient or the person is either
病人或者是其中之一
conscious or unconscious the complexity
有意识或无意识的复杂性
is either high or low and then you can
是高还是低然后你可以
adopt these techniques to similar
采用这些技术类似
creatures like monkeys and dogs and and
猴子和狗等生物
and mice that have very similar brains
和大脑 非常相似的老鼠
now of course you you point out that may
当然，你现在指出可能
not help you because we don't have a
不帮你， 因为我们没有
cortex you know and if I send a magnetic
皮质， 你 知道，如果我发送磁性
pulse into my iPhone or my computer it's
脉冲进入我的 iPhone 或我的 电脑吧
probably gonna break something so we
可能会破坏我们的东西
don't have that so what we need
没有我们需要的东西
ultimately we need a theory of
最终我们需要的理论
consciousness we can't just rely on our
意识我们不能只依靠我们
intuition our intuition is well yeah if
直觉我们的直觉 是好的，如果
somebody talks they're conscious however
有人说 他们有意识
then they're all these page children
然后他们就是所有这些页面的孩子
babies don't talk right but we believe
宝宝说话不对，但我们相信
that that the babies also have conscious
那个婴儿也有意识
experiences right and then there are
体验正确，然后 有
these patients I mentioned did and they
我提到的这些患者和他们
don't talk when you dream you can't talk
当你做梦 你不能说话时不要说话
because you're paralyzed so so what
因为你瘫痪了所以
would we ultimately need we can't just
将 我们最终需要，我们不能只
rely on our intuition we need a theory
依靠 我们的直觉， 我们需要一个理论
of constants that tells us what is it
常量 ，它告诉我们的是什么呢
about a piece of matter what is it about
关于一件事情是什么
a piece of highly excitable matter like
一件非常令人兴奋的事情
the brain or like a computer that give
大脑或类似的给计算机
rise to conscious experience we all
我们所有人都有意识地体验到
believe none of us believe anymore in
相信我们都不相信
the old story it's a soul but that used
旧的故事，它是一个灵魂， 但使用
to be the most common explanation that
是最常见的解释
most people accept that in still a lot
大多数人仍然接受这一点
of people today believe well there's
今天人们相信那里很好
there's God and doubt only us was a
有上帝，怀疑只有我们是一个
special thing that animals don't have
动物没有的特殊事物
Rene Descartes famously said a dog if he
Rene Descartes有一句名言，如果他是一只狗
hit it with your carriage may Yelp me
用你的马车打它可能会叫我
cry but it doesn't have this special
哭但没有这个特别的
thing it doesn't have the magic the
它没有魔力的东西
magic salt oh yeah
魔法盐哦是的
it doesn't have restaurants the soul now
它现在没有餐厅 的 灵魂
we believe that isn't the case anymore
我们相信情况不再如此
so what is the difference between brains
那么大脑之间有什么区别呢
and and these guys silicon and in
和这些家伙硅和在
particular once a behavior matches so if
特别是一旦行为 匹配，如果
you have cereal of tea or Alexan 20
你有谷物茶 或 Alexan 20
years from now that she can talk just as
从现在开始 ，她可以像 以前一样 说话
good as any possible human what counts
任何可能的人类都是重要的
do you have to say she's not conscious
你不得不说她没有意识吗？
in particular if she says it's of course
特别是如果她说这是当然的话
he well cuz I'm conscious you are sir
他很好， 因为我知道你是 先生
are you doing and she'll say well you
你在做什么，她会说你好
know they will generate some way to yeah
知道他们会产生某种方式，是的
she'll behave like a like a person now
她现在的表现就像一个人
there are several differences one is so
有一些差异就是这样
this relates to the problem they're very
这涉及到 他们非常 问题
hard
硬
why is consciousness a hard problem it's
为什么意识 是一个难题呢
because it's subjective right only I
因为它只是 我 的主观权利
have it for only I know I've direct
只有我知道我是直接的
experience of my own consciousness I
我 自己的 意识经验我
don't have experience your consciousness
没有经验你的意识
now I assume as a sort of Bayesian
现在我 假设是一种贝叶斯
person who believes in probability
人谁 的概率相信
theory and all of that you know I can do
理论和所有你 知道我能做的
I can do an abduction to the to the best
我可以绑架到最好的
available facts I deduce your brain is
可用的事实 我推断你的大脑是
very similar to mine if I put you in a
如果我把你放在一个非常相似的地方
scanner your brain is graphic on a
扫描你的大脑是图形的
behavior same with I do if if you know
如果你知道，行为与我一样
if I give you this muesli and ask you
如果我给你这个牛奶什锦早餐并 问你
how does it taste you tell me things
味道怎么样，你告诉我的事
that you know that that I would also say
你知道 我也会说
more or less I yes so I infer based on
或多或少 我是的所以我推断基于
all of that that you're conscious now
所有这些你现在都有意识的
we're silly I can't do that so there I
我很傻，我不能这样做，所以我
really need a theory that tells me what
真的需要一个能告诉我什么的理论
is it about above any system this or
它是关于任何系统的这个或
this it makes it conscious and we have
这使它有意识，我们有
such a theory yes so the the integrator
这样的理论 是的，所以整合者
information theory is but let me first
信息理论 只是让我先说
maybe his introduction for people are
也许他对人的介绍是
not familiar the car can you you talked
不熟悉这辆车， 你能谈谈吗？
a lot about pants psychism can you
很多关于裤子心理的事 可以
describe what physicalism versus dualism
描述物理主义与二元论的关系
this you mentioned the soul what what is
你提到了灵魂是什么
the history of that idea what the idea
那个想法的历史是 什么想法
psychism although the debate really out
心理虽然辩论 真的出来了
of which pan site-- chasm can emerge of
其中 pan site-- chasm可以出现
dualism versus physicalism or do you not
二元论与物理主义 或不是
see pants psychism is fitting into that
看裤子心理适合那个
and no you can argue there's some well
没有 ，你可以说有 一些很好
ok so let's step back so kemp psychism
好的 ，让我们退一步这么 精神的心理
is a very ancient belief that's been
是一个非常古老的信仰
around
周围
I mean Plato and us
我的意思是柏拉图和我们
talks about it modern philosophers talk
谈论现代哲学家 谈论 它
about it of course in Buddhism the idea
关于它当然 是佛教 的想法
is very prevalent that I mean the
非常普遍 ，我的意思是
different versions of it one version
它的不同版本有一个版本
says everything is in sold everything
说一切都卖了
arcs and stones and dogs and people and
弧形和石头和狗和人和
forests and iPhones all of us all right
森林和iPhone我们所有人都 可以
all matter is in soil that's sort of one
所有的事情都在土壤 中
version another version is that all
版本的另一个版本就是全部
biology all creatures small a large from
生物学所有生物都小而大
a single cell to a giant sequoia tree
一个单细胞到一棵巨大的红杉树
feel like something that's one I think
感觉像我认为的那样
is somewhat more realistic
更现实一些
so the different were willing me invite
所以不同的人愿意邀请我
feel like something I have have feeling
感觉像我有感觉的东西
have some kind of like some it may well
有点像它可能会有一些
be possible that it feels like something
有可能感觉像是某种东西
to be a Paramecium I think it's pretty
作为一个草履虫， 我觉得它很漂亮
likely it feels like something to be a
可能感觉像是某种东西
bee or a mouse or dog sure so okay so so
蜜蜂或老鼠或狗肯定 这么 好
that you can see that's also so pants
你可以看到那也是如此的裤子
item is very bored and you can to some
项目非常无聊，你可以去一些
people for example Bertrand Russell
人们， 例如 Bertrand Russell
try to advocate this for this idea it's
试着为这个想法提倡这个
called gazelian monism that that pant
那个喘气的叫做gazelian monism
psychism is really physics viewed from
从这个角度看，心理学就是物理学
the inside so the idea is that physics
内部所以这个想法就是物理学
is very good at describing relationship
非常善于描述关系
among objects like charges or like
在诸如收费之类的对象中
gravity all right you know this card the
重力你知道这张 卡了
relationship between curvature and mass
曲率与质量之间的关系
distribution okay that's the
分配好这就是
relationship among thing physics doesn't
事物物理学之间的关系没有
really describe the ultimate reality
真的描述了终极现实
itself it's just relationship among you
本身就是你们之间的关系
know quarks or all these other stuffs
知道夸克或所有这些其他的东西
from like a third-person observer yeah
像 第三人 观察员一样
yes and consciousness is what physics
是和意识是什么物理
feels from the inside so my conscious
从内心感受到我的意识
experience it's a way the physics of my
体验它是我的物理学的一种方式
brain particular my cortex feel from the
大脑特别是我的皮质感觉 来自
inside and so if you are Paramecium you
在里面，所以如果 你是草履虫你
gotta remember you see Paramecium well
得记住你很好看到草履虫
that's a pretty dumb creature this but
这是一个非常愚蠢的生物，但是
it has already a billion different
它已经十亿不同了
molecules probably you know five
分子可能你知道五个
thousand different proteins assembled in
一千种不同的蛋白质组装
a highly highly complex system that no
一个高度复杂的系统，没有
single person no computer system so far
到目前为止单身人士 没有电脑系统
on this planet has ever managed to
在 这个星球上 曾经成功
accurately simulate its complexity
准确地模拟其复杂性
vastly escapes us yes and it may well be
很大程度上逃避我们是的，它可能是
that that little thing feels like a tiny
那个 小东西感觉就像一个小小的东西
bit now it doesn't have a voice in the
现在，它 没有声音
head like me it doesn't have
像我这样的头，它没有
expectations you know it doesn't have
你知道它没有的期望
all that complex things but it may well
所有复杂的东西，但它 也 可能
if you like something yep so this is
如果你喜欢的话，那 就是这样
really interesting can we draw some
真有意思 我们可以画一些
lines and maybe try to understand the
线条，也许试着去理解
difference between life intelligence and
生活智力 与 生活智慧的区别
consciousness how do you see all of
意识你怎么看待所有的
those if you have to define what is a
那些，如果你必须定义什么 是
living thing what is a conscious thing
生物是什么是有意识的事情
and what is an intelligent thing do
什么是聪明的事情呢
those intermix for you or they totally
那些混合你或他们完全
separate okay so a that's a question
分开好吧这是一个问题
that we don't have a full answer right
我们没有完整的答案
after a lot of this stuff we're talking
经过很多这样的事情，我们正在谈论
about today is full of mysteries and
今天充满神秘色彩 和
fascinating ones right it was
这是令人着迷的
approximately can go to Aristotle who's
大约可以到亚里士多德谁的
probably the most important scientists
可能是最重要的科学家
and philosophers ever lived in certainly
和哲学家有史以来肯定
in Western culture he had this idea it's
在西方文化中他有这个想法
called halo morphism it's quite popular
被称为晕态态，它很受欢迎
these days that there are different
这些天 有 不同之处
forms of soul the soul is really the
灵魂的形式真正的灵魂
form of something he saw he says all
他看到他所说的一切形式
biological creature have a vegetative
生物有植物
soul that's life principle today we
灵魂是我们今天的生活原则
think we understand something molded
我认为我们理解了一些 模塑
it's biochemistry nonlinear
这是生物化学的非线性
thermodynamics all right then he says
他说，热力学可以
they have a sensitive so only animals
他们只有敏感的动物
and humans have also a sensitive soul or
人类也 有敏感的灵魂或者
an appetitive soul they they can see
他们可以看到一个食欲的灵魂
they can smell and they have drives they
他们可以闻到，他们有驱动他们
want to repeat use they want to eat etc
想重复使用他们想吃的等等
and then only humans have what he called
然后只有人类拥有他所谓的
a rational soul okay right and that idea
一个理性的灵魂没错， 那个想法
that made it into christen dome and then
这 使它成为了教堂 圆顶然后
the rational soul is the one that lives
理性的灵魂就是生命的灵魂
forever he was very young he wasn't
永远他很 年轻他不是
really I mean different readings of
我真的是指不同的读物
Aristotle give different was that did he
亚里士多德给出的不同就是他
believe that rational soul was immortal
相信理性的灵魂是不朽的
or not I probably think he didn't but
或不，我可能认为他没有
then of course that made it into its who
当然 ，这使它成为 谁
Plato in the Christianity and then this
柏拉图在基督教 然后这个
world became immortal and then became
世界变得不朽然后变成了
the connection where after to God now
现在 在上帝之后的联系
you so you ask me essentially you what
你这么基本上你问我什么
does our modern conception of these free
我们对这些自由的现代概念吗？
Aristotle would have called them
亚里士多德会打电话给他们
different forms life we think we know
我们认为 我们知道不同形式的生活
something about it at least life on this
关于它的一些事情，至少生活在此
planet right although we don't
虽然我们没有，但是 行星正确
understand how to originate it but it's
了解如何发起它，但它是
it's been difficult to rigorously pin
很难严格确定
down you see this in modern definition
你在现代 定义中 看到这一点
of death it's in de facto right now
死亡 现在事实上已经存在了
there's a conference ongoing again that
还有一个会议正在进行中
tries to defined
试图定义
legally and medically what is death it
从法律上和医学上讲，死亡是什么
used to be very simple des is you stop
以前很简单 des 就是你停下来
breathing your heart stops beating
呼吸你的心脏停止跳动
you're dead right yeah totally
你死了 是的完全是的
unconverted
未转换
if you're unsure you wait another 10
如果你不确定你再等 10点
minutes if the patient doesn't breathe
如果患者不呼吸则需要几分钟
you know he's
你知道他的
well now we have ventilators we have
现在好了，我们有呼吸机，我们有
half a pacemaker so it's much more
半个心脏起搏器，所以它更多
difficult to define what death is
难以界定死亡是什么
typically des is defined at the end of
通常des定义在结尾处
life and life is defined before yes so
生生之前定义是 这样
before that okay so we don't have really
在那之前好吧所以我们 没有真的
very good definitions intelligence we
我们 非常 好的定义智能
don't have a rigorous data definition we
我们没有严格的数据定义
know something how to measure it's
知道如何测量它的东西
called IG IQ or G factors right and and
称为IG IQ或G因子对和
we're beginning to build it in in a
我们开始用 它 来构建 它
narrow sense right like go alphago and
狭隘的感觉就像去 alphago和
and and and Watson and you know Google
和和和 华生，你知道谷歌
cars and uber cars and all of that that
汽车和超级汽车以及所有这些
still narrow AI and some people are
仍然缩小AI和一些人
thinking about the artificial general
考虑 人工一般
intelligence but roughly as we said
情报，但大致如我们所说
before it's something lose ability to
在它失去能力之前
learn and to adapt to new environments
学习并 适应 新 环境
but that is as I said also it's radical
但就像我说的那样，这是激进的
difference from experience and it's very
与经验的差异，非常
unclear if you build a machine that has
目前还不清楚，如果你建立具有机
AGI it's not at all a priori it's not at
AGI它根本不是 先验，它不是
all clear that this machine will have
一切都 清楚， 这台机器将有
consciousness it may or may not so let's
意识它可能会也可能不会如此
ask it the other way do you think if you
问你另一种方式，如果你认为
were to try to build an artificial
试图 建立一个人造的
general intelligence system do you think
你认为一般情报系统
figuring out how to build artificial
搞清楚 如何建造人造的
consciousness would help you get to an
意识 会帮助你达到目标
AGI so or put another way do you think
AGI 所以或者你想的另一种方式
intelligent requires consciousness in
智能需要意识
human it goes hand in hand
人类它携手并进
in human or I think Ambala G
在人类或我认为Ambala G.
consciousness intelligence goes hand in
意识智慧进入
hand quite a solution because the the
手很有 解决方案，因为
brain evolved to be highly complex
大脑进化得非常复杂
complexity via the theory integrated
通过整合理论的复杂性
information theory is sort of ultimately
信息理论最终是一种
is what is closely tied to consciousness
与意识密切相关的是什么
ultimately it's causal power upon itself
最终 它是 自身 的因果力量
and so in evolution evolved systems they
所以在进化演化 系统中他们
go together in artificial system
在人工系统中一起去
particular in digital machines they do
特别是他们做的数字机器
not go together and if you asked me
如果你 问我，不要一起去
point-blank
直射的
is Alexa 20 point O in the year 2041 she
是Alexa 在2041年的 20 点O她
can easily pass every Turing test is she
她可以轻松通过每一次图灵测试
conscious no even if she claims she's
即使她声称自己也没有意识到
concerts in fact you could even do a
音乐会其实你甚至可以做一个
more radical version of this thought
更激进的 这个想法的 版本
experiment we can build a computer
实验我们可以建立一台电脑
simulation of the human brain you know
你知道人 脑 模拟
what Henry Markram
什么亨利马克拉姆
in the Blue Brain Project or the human
在蓝脑项目或人类
brain project in Switzerland is trying
瑞士的大脑项目正在努力
to do let's grant him all the success so
让我们给他所有的成功
in ten years we have this perfect
在十年中，我们有这个完美
simulation of the human brain
模拟人脑
every new one is simulated in
每个新的都是模拟的
hasil Amex and it has motor neurons it
hasil Amex 它有运动神经元
has a Ibaka's area and of course it'll
有一个Ibaka的 区域，当然它会
talk and it'll say hi I just woken up I
说话，它会说你好我只是醒了我
feel great okay even that computer
甚至那台电脑也 感觉很好
simulation that can imprint some map on
可以在某些地图上打印的模拟
to your brain will not be conscious why
对你的大脑 不会有意识的 原因
because it simulates it's a difference
因为它模拟它是一个区别
between the simulated and the real so it
在 模拟 和真实之间 如此
simulates the behavior salted with
模拟盐渍的行为
consciousness it might be it will if
意识可能会如果
it's done properly will have all the
它做得恰到好处将拥有所有
intelligence that that particular person
那个特定的人的情报
they're simulating has but simulating
他们模拟但有模拟
intelligence is not the same as having
智力与拥有不同
conscious experiences and I'll give you
有意识的经历， 我会给 你
a really nice metaphor that engineers
工程师的一个非常好的比喻
and physicists stupidly get I can write
和物理学家愚蠢地得到我可以写
down in Stein's field equation nine or
在斯坦因的场方程 九或
ten equations that describe the link in
10个方程描述 中 的链接
general relativity between curvature and
曲率与曲率的广义相对论
and mass I can do that I can run this on
和大众，我可以做到，我可以运行此
my laptop to to predict that the sample
我的笔记本电脑 要预测 样品
the black hole at the center of our
我们中心的 黑洞
galaxy will be so massive that it will
星系将是如此巨大，它会
twist space-time around it so no light
扭曲它周围的时空，所以没有光
can escape I it's a black hole right but
可以逃脱我这是一个黑洞， 但是
funny have you ever won that why doesn't
有趣的是你有没有赢过那个为什么 没有
this computer simulation suck me in
这个计算机模拟 让我感到厌烦
alright it simulates gravity but it
好吧，它 模拟重力，但它
doesn't have the causal power of gravity
没有引力的因果力
it's a huge difference so it's a
这是一个巨大的差异所以它是一个
difference between the real and and the
真实和真实的区别
simulator just like it doesn't get wet
模拟器就像它不会被 弄湿
inside the computer when the computer
电脑里面的电脑
runs code that simulates a weather storm
运行模拟天气风暴的代码
and so in order to have to have
所以为了必须拥有
artificial continents you have to give
你要给的人造大陆
it the same causal power as a human
它与人类具有相同的因果关系
brain yes you have to build so-called a
大脑是的，你必须建立所谓的一个
neuromorphic machine that has hardware
具有硬件的神经形态机器
that is very similar to the human brain
这与 人类大脑 非常相似
not a digital clock for normal computer
不是 普通电脑 的数字 时钟
so that's just to clarify though you
所以这只是为了澄清你
think that consciousness is not required
认为意识不要求
to create human level intelligence it
创造人类智慧 吧
seems to accompany in the human brain
似乎伴随着人类的大脑
but for a machine not of court so maybe
但对于一台非 法庭 的机器 ，也许
just because this is AGI let's dig in a
只因为这是 AGI 让我们深入研究
little bit about what we mean by
关于我们的意思
intelligence so one thing is the G
智力所以有一点是G
factor these kind of IQ tests of
这些智商 测试的因素
intelligence but I think if you maybe
情报， 但我 想如果你可能
another way to say so in 2040 2050
2050年2050年另一种说法
people will have Siri that is
人们会有 Siri
just really impressive do you think
你觉得这真是令人印象深刻吗？
people will say serious intelligent yes
人们会说 严肃聪明的是
intelligence is this amorphous thing so
智能本是无定形的事情 ，所以
it to be intelligent it seems like you
它看起来像你一样聪明
have to have some kind of connections
必须有某种 联系
with other human beings in a sense that
在 某种意义上 其他人 说
you have to impress them with your
你必须用你的印象来打动他们
intelligence and their feels you have to
智慧和 他们的感受你必须
somehow operate in this world full of
以某种方式在这个世界 充满活力
humans and for that there feels like
人类和那样的 感觉就像
there has to be something like
必须有类似的东西
consciousness so you think you can have
意识所以你认为你可以 拥有
just the world's best natural NLP system
这 是世界上最好的自然NLP系统
natural language understanding a
自然语言理解
generation and that will be that will
一代就会那样
get us happy and say you know what we've
让我们开心，并说你知道我们是什么
created an AGI I don't know happy no
创造了一个AGI我不知道快乐没有
well yes I do believe we can get what we
是的， 我相信我们可以得到我们的东西
call high-level functional intelligence
称 高级功能智能
particular sort of the G you know this
你知道这个特别的G
this fluid like intelligence that we
这种流动就像我们的智慧一样
cherish particularly the place like MIT
特别珍惜麻省理工学院这样的地方
right in in in machines I see a boy I
在机器中我看到 一个男孩我
know reasons and I see a lot of reason
知道原因，我看到很多理由
to believe it's gonna happen very you
相信它会 发生在你身上
know over the next 50 years of 30 years
了解 未来50年的30年
so for beneficial AI for creating an AI
因此， 对于创建AI的有益AI
system that's so you mentioned ethics
系统，你提到道德
that is exceptionally intelligent but
这非常聪明但是
also does not do does you know aligns
也不做你知道吗？
its values with our values as humanity
它的价值观与我们作为人类的价值观
do you think then in his consciousness
你觉得 他的 意识 吗？
yes I think that that is a very good
是的，我认为那是非常好的
argument that if we're concerned about
如果我们 担心的话
AI and the threat of a aisle and Nick
AI和 过道和尼克 的威胁
Bostrom accidentally said I think having
博斯特罗姆不小心说我觉得有
an intelligent that has empathy right
一个有同理心的聪明人
why do we find abusing a dog why do most
为什么我们发现滥用狗为什么最多
of us find that apartment abusing any
我们发现 公寓滥用任何
animal right why do we find that
动物权利为什么我们 找到了
apartment because we have this thing
公寓，因为我们 有这个东西
called empathy which if you look at the
如果你看一下就 称为移情
Greek really means feeling with I feel a
希腊语真的意味着我感觉到了
compass of empathy I have feeling with
我感受到的同理心的指南针
you
您
I see somebody else suffer that isn't
我看到其他人遭受的不是
even my conspecific it's not a person
即便是我的同意也不是一个人
it's not a lot but it's not my wife or
这不是很多，但 不是我的妻子或
my kids it's it's a dog but I feel
我的孩子，这是一只狗， 但我觉得
naturally most of us not all of us most
很自然地，我们大多数人不是最重要的
of us will feel emphatic and so it may
我们会感到有力，所以它可能会
well be in the long-term interest of
以及在 的长远 利益
survival of Homo sapiens sapiens that if
如果人类的生存，那么智人 （ Homo sapiens sapiens）的存活率
we do build AGI and it really becomes
我们建立AGI， 它真的变成了
very powerful
很强大
that it has an emphatic response and
它有一个强烈的反应和
doesn't just exterminate humanity so as
不只是消灭人类，从而
part of the full conscious experience to
全部意识体验的一部分
create a consciousness artificial or in
创造一种人工或意识的意识
our human consciousness do you think
你认为我们的人类意识
fear maybe we're gonna get into the
恐惧也许我们会进入
earlier days with Mitch and so on but do
早些时候与 米奇 等等，但做
you think fear and suffering are
你认为恐惧和痛苦是
essential to have consciousness do you
对你有意识至关重要
have to have the full range of
必须拥有全方位 的
experience of it to have a system that
拥有一个系统的经验
has experience or can you have a system
有经验或者你有一个系统
that only has a very particular kinds of
只有 一种非常特殊的种类
very positive experiences look you can
非常积极的经历看起来你可以
have in principle you can people have
在 原则上，你可以人
done this in the rat where you implanted
在你 植入 的老鼠身上做到这一点
electrode in the hypothalamus the
电极在下丘脑中
pleasure center of the head and the rat
头部和老鼠的快乐中心
stimulated some above and beyond
刺激了一些超越
anything else it doesn't care about food
其他任何不关心 食物的东西
or natural sex or drink anymore to
或自然性或不再 喝
stimulate itself because it's it's such
刺激自己因为就是这样
a pleasurable feeling I guess it's like
一种令人愉快的感觉， 我猜它就像
an orgasm just you have you know all day
一个高潮只是你 整天 都知道
long and so a priori I see no reason why
很长，所以先验我看不​​出理由
you need different forever I need a
你需要 永远 不同 我需要一个
great variety now clearly to survive
种类繁多，现在显然可以生存
that wouldn't work but if I'd engineered
这不会奏效，但如果我设计的话
artificially I don't think I don't think
人为地我不认为我不思考
you need a great variety of conscious
你需要各种各样的意识
expense you could have just pleasure or
花费 你可以享受的乐趣
just fear it might be a terrible
只是害怕它可能是一个可怕的
existence but I think that's possible at
存在， 但我认为这是可能的
least on conceptual logical count cause
至少在概念逻辑计数原因上
any real creature whether artificially
任何真实的生物，无论是 人为的
engineered you want to give it fear the
设计你想让它害怕
fear of extinction that we all have and
害怕我们都拥有 和 灭绝的灭绝
you also want to give it a positive
你也想给它一个积极的
appetitive states states that it wants
食欲 状态表明它想要
to that you want the Machine encouraged
为了你想要机器鼓励
to do because if they give the Machine
要做，因为如果他们给 机器
positive feedback so you mentioned
积极的反馈， 所以你 提到
pants.i chasm to jump back a little bit
pants.i裂口跳回来一点点
you know everything having some kind of
你知道一切都有某种
mental property how do you go from there
精神财产你怎么去那里
to something like human consciousness so
这样的 人类意识
everything having some elements of
一切都有一些元素
consciousness - well is there something
意识 - 有什么东西
special about human consciousness what
关于人类意识的特别之处
so so just it's not everything like a
所以所以只是它不是一切都像一个
spoon there's no I the the form of Pam
勺子， 我不是Pam的形式
Jochum
约胡姆
I think about doesn't ask I
我想不会问我
consciousness - anything like this the
意识- 这样的事情
spoon
勺
my liver however it is the theory the
然而，我的肝脏是理论
integrated information theory does say
综合信息理论确实说
that system even ones that look from the
那个系统甚至是从那个看起来的系统
outside relatively simple Atlee if they
外面相对简单的Atlee如果他们
have this internal causal power they are
他们有这种内在的因果关系
they it does feel like something the
他们确实感觉像是什么东西
theory a poet doesn't see anything
理论诗人 并没有看到任何东西
what's special about human biologically
人类在生物学上有什么特别之处
we know what the one thing that special
我们知道那件特别的东西是什么
about human is we speak and we have a
关于人类，我们说话， 我们有 一个
overblown sense of our own importance
夸大了我们自己的重要性
right
对
we believe we exceptional and where does
我们相信我们非常出色， 在哪里
God's give - - into the universe but the
上帝赐予 -   - 进入宇宙 而不是 宇宙
but behaviorally the main thing that we
但行为是我们的主要事情
have we can plant we can plan over the
我们可以种植我们可以计划的
long term and we have language and that
长期，我们有 语言和 那
gives us enormous amount of power and
给了我们巨大的力量 和
that's why we are there the current
这就是为什么我们在那里
dominant species on the planet
这个星球上的 优势种
so you mentioned God you grow up a
所以你提到上帝你长大 了
devout Roman Catholic you know Roman
虔诚的罗马天主教 你知道罗马
Catholic family so you know with
天主教家庭 让你知道
consciousness you're sort of exploring
你正在探索的意识
some really deeply fundamental human
一些真正深刻的人类
things that religion also touches on so
宗教也触及的事情
where does where does religion fit into
宗教在哪里适合
your thinking about consciousness and
你对意识和思想的思考
you've you've grown throughout your life
你，你已经长大了你的一生
and changed your views and religion as
并改变了你的观点和 宗教信仰
far as I understand yeah I mean I'm now
据我所知，是的，我的意思是我现在
much closer to so I'm not a Roman
更接近所以我不是罗马人
Catholic anymore I don't believe there's
天主教徒，我不相信那里
sort of this God the God I was I was
在某种程度上， 我就是上帝
educated to believe in you know sits
有教养相信你知道 坐着
somewhere in the fullness of time I'll
我会 在一个充满时间的某个地方
be united in some sort of everlasting
在某种永恒中团结起来
bliss I just don't see any evidence for
幸福我只是没有看到任何 证据
that look the world the night is large
看起来世界的夜晚很大
and full of Wonders right there are many
并且充满了奇迹 ，有很多
things that I don't understand I think
我认为 我 不明白的 事情
many things that we as a cult I look we
我们看待我们的许多事情
don't even understand more than four
甚至不懂 四个以上
percent of all the universe right dark
所有 宇宙中黑暗的 百分比
matter dark energy we have no idea what
重要的是暗能量，我们不知道是什么
it is maybe it's lost socks what do I
也许它已经失去 了我的 袜子
know so so all I can tell you is it's a
知道所以我可以 告诉你的是它是一个
sort of mom my current religious or
有点妈妈我现在的宗教或
spiritual sentiments much closer to some
精神情绪更接近一些
form of Buddhism can you - without the
佛教的形式可以 - 没有
reincarnation
投胎
unfortunately there's no evidence for in
不幸的是， 没有证据表明
reincarnation so can you describe the
转世所以 你能描述一下吗？
way Buddhism sees the world a little bit
佛教的方式看待世界一点点
well so the you know they talk about so
所以你知道他们这么说
when when I spent several meetings with
什么时候我和他开了几次会
with the Dalai Lama and what always
与达赖喇嘛一如既往
impressed me
让 我 印象深刻
about him he really unlike for example
关于他，他真的不像例如
at either the Pope was some Cardinal he
无论 是 教皇还是 红衣主教
always emphasized minimizing the
总是强调最小化
suffering of all creatures so they have
他们拥有 所有生物的痛苦
this from the early beginning they look
从一开始他们看起来就是这样
at suffering in all creatures not just
在所有生物的痛苦中不仅仅是
in people but in in everybody this
在人群中但在每个人身上
universal and of course by degrees right
普遍的，当然还有正确的程度
in an animal
在动物中
Jerell will have less is less capable of
Jerell将有较少的能少
suffering than a then a well developed
痛苦比当时发达
normally developed human and they think
通常发达的人类，他们认为
consciousness pervades in this universe
意识弥漫在这个宇宙中
and they have these techniques you know
他们有 你 知道的 这些技巧
you can think of them like mindfulness
你可以把它们想象成 正念
etc and meditation that tries to access
尝试 访问的等等和冥想
sort of what they claim of this more
他们对此的要求更多了
fundamental aspect of reality I'm not
现实的基本方面我不是
sure it's more fundamentalist I think
我认为这确实是更原教旨主义者
about it there's a physical and then
关于它有一个物理然后
this is inside view consciousness and
这是观点意识和内在
those are the two aspects that's the
那些是两个方面的
only thing I've I have access to in my
我唯一可以访问的东西
life and you gotta remember my conscious
生活，你必须 记住我的意识
experience and your conscious experience
经验和你的意识体验
comes prior to anything you know about
在你知道的任何事情之前
physics comes PI to knowledge about the
物理学来到PI知识
universe and atoms and super strings and
宇宙和原子和超级弦和
molecules and all of that the only thing
分子和所有的 唯一
you directly are acquainted with is this
你直接认识的就是这个
world that's populated with with things
充满了东西的世界
in images and and sounds in your head
在你头脑中的图像和声音
and touches on all of that I actually
并实际上触及了所有这些
have a question so and it sounds like
有一个问题，听起来像
you kind of have a rich life you talk
你说话 的时候有丰富的 生活
about rock climbing and it seems like
关于攀岩，它 似乎
you really love literature and
你真的很喜欢文学和
consciousness is all about experiencing
意识就是体验
things so do you think that has helped
事情你认为 这有帮助
your research on this topic
你对这个主题的研究
yes particular if you think about it the
是的， 如果你仔细想想就行了
the various states so for example you do
各种状态，例如你这样做
our climbing or now I do
我们的攀登或现在我做
oink-cool going and a bike every day you
你 每天 都去oink-cool 和 骑自行车
can get into this thing called the zone
可以进入这个叫做 区域的 东西
and I've always I want to I want to Bob
我一直想要 鲍勃
about a particular with respect to
关于某个特定的
consciousness because it's a strangely
意识，因为它是一个奇怪的
addictive state you want to you want to
你 想你上瘾的状态 要
appear I mean once people have it once
看来我的意思是一旦人们拥有它一次
you want to keep on going back to it and
要继续 退后它 和
you wonder what is it so addicting about
你想知道它是如此令人上瘾的东西
it and I think it's the experience of
它和我认为这是经验
almost close to pure experience because
几乎接近纯粹的经验， 因为
in this in the zone you're not conscious
在这个区域，你没有意识到
over in a voice anymore but there's
在一个声音中已经过 了但是有
always this inner voice nagging you
总是这种内心的声音唠叨着你
right you have to do this you have to do
你必须这样做你必须这样做
that you have to pay your taxes yet this
那你必须缴纳税款
fight was your ex and all of those
战斗是你的前任和所有这些
things are always there but when you're
事情永远存在，但是当你的时候
in the zone all of that is gone
在该区域所有 这 一切 都消失了
and your justice in this wonderful state
和你在这美好状态下的正义
while you're fully out in the world a
当你完全在世界上时 a
job you're climbing or you're hauling or
你正在攀爬的 工作 ，或者你在拖车或工作
biking or doing soccer what or whatever
骑自行车或做足球什么或其他什么
you're doing and sort of consciousness
你正在做的和排序 的 意识
sort of is is your all action or in this
是你的所有行动或在此
case of pure experience you're not
纯粹的经验，你不是
action at all but in both cases you
除了两种情况你都 行动
experience some aspect of of can't you
体验某些方面的不了你
touch some basic part of off of
摸掉的一些基本组成部分
conscious existence that is so basic and
有意识的存在是如此基本 和
so deeply satisfying you I think you
我觉得你 很满意
touch the root of being that's really
触及存在的根源
what you're touching there you're
你在 那里 接触 到的是什么
getting close to the root of being and
越来越接近存在 的根源
that's very different from intelligence
这与情报非常不同
so what do you think about the
所以你想想什么
simulation hypothesis simulation theory
模拟假设模拟理论
the idea that we all live in a computer
我们都住在电脑里的想法
simulation have you knowit's justice for
模拟让你 知道 正义
her I think it's as likely as the
她认为这和它一样可能
hypothesis had engaged hundreds of
假设原本从事 数百
scholars for many centuries are we all
几个世纪以来的学者都是我们所有人
just existing in the mind of God right
只是在现有的神 权 思想
right and this is just a modern version
对 ，这 只是 一个现代版本
of it it's it's it's it's equally
这就是它是一样的
plausible people love talking about
似是而非的人喜欢谈论
these sorts of things I know their book
这些 东西我都知道他们的书
written is about the simulation
写的是关于模拟
hypothesis if that's what people want to
假设这是 人们想要的
do that's fine it seems rather esoteric
做到这 一点 似乎相当深奥
it's never testable but it's not useful
它永远不可测试，但它没用
for you to think of in those terms so
你可以 用这些术语 来 思考
maybe connecting to the questions of
也许连接到的问题
free will which you've talked about I
你谈到我的自由意志
think vaguely wherever you saying that
无论你说什么，都要模糊地 思考
the idea that there's no free will it
认为没有 自由 意志的想法
makes you very uncomfortable so what do
会让你感到非常不舒服
you think about free will and from that
你想想 自由 意志 ，并从该
you from a physics perspective or a
你是从物理学的角度来看 的
consciousness perspective what is it all
意识透视是什么 一切
okay so from the physics perspective
从物理学的角度来看也好
leaving inside quantum mechanics we
离开量子力学我们
believe we live in a fully deterministic
相信我们生活在一个完全确定的
world right but then comes of course
世界的权利，但当然来了
quantum mechanics so now we know that
量子力学所以现在我们知道了
certain things on principle not
某些 事情原则上没有
predictable which as you said I prefer
可以预测，正如你所说，我更喜欢
because the idea that at the initial
因为最初的想法
condition of the universe and then
宇宙的条件，然后
everything else we're just acting out
其他一切我们只是表现 出来
the initial condition of the universe
宇宙的初始条件
that doesn't that doesn't mean it's not
这并不意味着它不是
a romantic notion no certainly not right
一个浪漫的概念， 当然不对
now when it comes to consciousness I
现在谈到意识我
think we do have certain freedom we are
认为我们确实拥有一定的自由
much more constrained by a physics of
受到物理学的限制
course and by our past and by our own
当然，我们的过去和我们 自己
conscious desires and what our parents
有意识的欲望和我们的 父母
told us and
告诉我们和
what our environment tells us we we all
我们的环境告诉我们我们所有人
know that our there's hundreds of
知道我们有几百
experiments that show how we can be
实验证明，证明我们如何能够
influenced but finally in the in the
受影响但终于在了
final analysis when you make a lifetime
当你做一辈子归根结底
talk not really about critical decision
谈论不是关键的决定
what you really think should I marriage
你 真正认为 我 应该 结婚
should I go to this school that could
我应该去这所学校吗？
should I take this job is that job
我应该接受这份 工作 就是那份工作
should I cheat on my taxes or not these
我应该欺骗 我的税收还是不要 这些
sort of these are things what you really
这些都是你真正的事情
deliberate and I think under those
故意，我想在那些
conditions you are as free as you can be
条件你尽可能自由
when you when you bring your entire
当你带上你的 全部时
being anti conscious being to that
反对意识到这一点
question and try to analyze it on all
问题并尝试分析 它 在所有
the the various condition and then you
各种 条件 ，然后你
take you make a decision you are as free
带你做出你自由的决定
as you can ever be that is I think what
正如你所能 做到的那样 ，我想 是什么
what free will is it's not a will that's
什么自由意志是它不是一个意志 的
totally free to do anything it wants
完全自由地做任何想做的事
that's not possible right so as Jack
杰克 ，这是 不可能的
mentioned yet you actually read a blog
提到你实际上读过一篇博客
about books you've read amazing books
关于书籍你读过很棒的书
from I'm Russian from Bulgakov cha oh
从我来自 布尔加科夫的 俄罗斯 茶哦
yeah Neil Gaiman Carl Sagan Murakami so
是啊Neil Gaiman Carl Sagan Murakami所以
what is a book that early in your life
你生命早期的书是什么？
transformed the way you saw the world
改变了你看世界的方式
something that changed your life
改变 你 生活的 东西
Nietzsche against did that spokes are
尼采反对这样做 辐条
twister because he talks about some of
twister因为他谈到了一些
these problems you know he was one of
这些 问题你知道他是其中之一
the first discoverer of the unconscious
无意识 的第一个 发现者
this is you know a little bit before for
这是你之前知道的
it when it was in the air and you know
它时， 它是在 空气 中 ，你知道
he makes all these claims that people
他把所有这些主张都说成了人
sort of under the guise or under the
排序下 的幌子或下
mask of charity actually are very non
慈善面具实际上非常非
charitable so he sort of really the
慈善所以他那种真正 的
first discoverer of the great land of
第一个发现者 的伟大土地
the of the unconscious and that that
无意识的那个和那个
really struck me and what do you think
我真的很震惊 ，你怎么想
what do you think about the unconscious
你怎么看待无意识
what do you think about Freud we think
您如何看待我们认为的弗洛伊德
about these ideas what's what's just
关于这些想法 是什么才是正义的
like dark matter in the universe what's
像宇宙中 的 暗物质 是 什么
over there in that unconscious a lot I
在那里，在 那 无意识中我很多
mean much more than we think this is
意思是比我们认为这 是更
what a lot of last hundred years of
正是很多上百年 的
research has shown so I think he was a
研究表明，我认为他是一个
genius misguided towards the end but he
天才被误导到最后，但 他
was all he started out as a
他开始时只是 一个人
neuroscientist but he contributed he did
神经科学家，但 他贡献了他
the studies on the on the lamprey he
关于七鳃鳗的研究他
contributed himself to the neon
为霓虹灯做出了贡献
hypothesis the idea that there
假设那里的想法
discreet units that we call nerve cells
我们称之为神经细胞的 谨慎 单位
now and then he started then he he vote
他现在开始然后投票
you know about the unconscious and I
你知道无意识和我
think it's to there's lots of stuff
认为这是有 很多东西
happening you feel this particular when
发生 这种 情况时 你会感觉到这一点
you're in a relationship and it breaks a
你处于一种关系中并打破 了
son alright and then you have this
儿子 好吧，然后 你有这个
terrible you can have love and hate and
可怕的是，你可以拥有爱与恨
lust and anger and all of its mixed in
欲望和愤怒，所有的混合在一起
and when you try to analyze yourself why
当你试图分析自己为什么
am I so upset it's very very difficult
我很难过，这非常困难
to penetrate to those basements those
渗透到 那些 地下室
caverns in your mind because the prying
因为撬动而在你脑海中的洞穴
eyes of conscience doesn't have access
良心的 眼睛 无法 进入
to those but they're they are made in
对那些人来说 ， 他们是制造的
the amygdala or you know lots of other
杏仁核或者您知道很多 其他
places they make you upset or angry or
地方，他们让你烦恼或愤怒 或
sad or depressed and it's very difficult
悲伤或沮丧 ，这是非常困难的
to try to actually uncover the reason
试着真正揭开 原因
you can go to a shrink you can talk with
你可以去一个可以与之交谈的收缩
your friend endlessly
你的朋友无休止地
you couldn't start finally a story why
你最后无法开始讲故事的原因
this happened why you love you or don't
这就发生了为什么你爱你或不爱你
love or whatever but you don't really
爱或其他什么， 但 你不是真的
know whether that's actually the with
知道这是否真的与之相关
that that actually happened because you
这实际上是 因为你而 发生的
simply don't have access to those parts
根本无法访问 这些部分
of the brain and they're very powerful
大脑 ， 他们非常 强大
you think that's a feature or a bug of
你认为这是一个功能或错误
our brain the fact that we have this
我们的大脑是我们拥有这个的事实
deep difficult to dive into subconscious
深陷难以潜入潜意识
I think it's a feature because otherwise
我认为这是一个功能，否则
look we are we are see is like any other
看看我们是我们 看到的是像任何其他
brain or nervous system or computer we
大脑或神经系统或计算机我们
are severely band-limited if we if
如果我们这样做，则会受到严格的限制
everything I do every emotion I feel
我感受到的每一种感情
every my movements I make if all of that
我所做的每一个动作都是如此
had to be another control of
必须是另一个控制
consciousness I couldn't I I couldn't I
意识我不能II我不能
wouldn't be here all right so so what
什么都不会这样
you do early on your brain you have to
你做到早在你的大脑 ，你必须
be conscious when you learn things like
当你学习像这样的东西时要有意识
typing or like riding on a bike but then
打字或喜欢骑自行车然后
you what you do you train up or out I
你做什么训练你训练 我
think that involve basal ganglia and
认为 涉及基底节和
stratum you bear you train up different
你承受的阶层训练不同
parts of your brain and then once you do
你的大脑 的部分，然后一旦你做
it automatically like typing you can
它会自动像字，就可以
show you do it much faster without even
显示你甚至没有更快地做到这一点
thinking about it because you've got
考虑一下，因为你有
this highly specialized what Francis
这个高度专业化的弗朗西斯
Crick and I called zombie agents that
克里克和 我打电话给僵尸特工
are sort of that taking care of that
有点像那样 照顾
while your consciousness can sort of
而你的意识可以那样
worry about the abstract sense of the
担心抽象的 感觉
text you want to write and I think
我想你想写的文字
that's true for many many things but for
这对许多事情都是 如此 ， 但 对于
the things like all the fights you have
像 你 所有的战斗之类的东西
with the ex-girlfriend things that you
与前女友的事情，你
would think are not useful to still
会认为仍然没用
linger somewhere in the sub
徘徊在潜艇的某个地方
conscious so that seems like a bug that
有意识的 让似乎是一个错误 ，
it would stay there you think it would
它会留在那里 你认为它 会
be better if you can analyze it and then
如果你 可以分析它， 那就 更好了
get it out of there or just forget it
把它拿出来 或者忘掉它
ever happened you know that that seems a
曾经发生过 你知道那似乎是一个
very buggy kind of well yeah but in
非常马车好的， 但是 在
general we don't have and that's
一般我们没有， 那是
probably functional we don't have an
可能功能我们没有
ability unless it's extremely of cases
能力，除非极端情况
clinical dissociations right when people
临床解体时的人
are heavily abused when they completely
他们完全被严重滥用
repress them they the memory but that
镇压他们，他们的记忆但
doesn't happen in in in you know in
不会发生在你所知道的中
normal people if we don't have an
普通人， 如果我们 没有
ability to remove traumatic memories and
能够消除创伤记忆 和
of course we suffer from that on the
当然，我们从上吃亏
other hand probably if you had the
另一方面， 如果你有的话
ability to constantly wipe your memory
不断擦拭你的记忆 能力
you probably do it to an extent that
你可能在某种程度上 这样做
isn't useful to you
对你没用
so yeah it's a good question with the
所以是它与一个很好的问题
balance so on the books is Jack
杰克，书上的平衡就是这样
mentioned correct me if I'm wrong but
如果我错了，请提及我
broadly speaking in academia and the
广泛地 说，在学术界和学术界
different scientific disciplines
不同的科学学科
certainly an engineering reading
当然是工程阅读
literature seems to be a rare pursuit
文学似乎是一种难得的追求
perhaps I'm wrong in this but that's in
也许我错了，但那 是 在
my experience most people are read much
我的经历大多数 人都读得很多
more technical text and do not sort of
更多的技术文本和不排序 的
escape or seek truth in literature it
在文学中逃避或寻求真理 吧
seems like you do so what do you think
好像你这样做，你怎么想
is the value what do you think
价值你怎么想？
literature asks the pursuit of
文学要求追求
scientific truth do you think it's good
科学真理你觉得这很好吗？
it's useful for given access to much
它对于给定访问权限非常有用
wider array of human experiences how
更广泛的 人类经历如何
valuable do you think it is well if you
如果你认为这很好，你认为有价值吗？
want to understand human nature and
想要了解人性和
nature in general then I think you have
一般的性质然后我认为 你有
to better understand wide variety of
更好地了解 各种各样的
experiences not just sitting in a lab
体验不只是坐在实验室里
staring at a screen and having a face
盯着屏幕看脸
flashed onto you've won a million
闪过你已赢得一百万
pushing a button that's what that's what
按下按钮就是那个
I used to do that for most psychologists
我曾经为大多数心理学家这样做过
do there's nothing wrong with that but
这样做有什么不妥 ，但
you need to consider lots of other
你需要 考虑 很多其他
strange states you know and literature
你知道的奇怪状态 和文学
is a shortcut for this well yeah as
这是一个捷径， 是 的
literature that's that's what literature
那些文学就是文学
is all about all sorts of interesting
所有这些都是 有趣的
experiences that people have the you
人们 拥有你的 经历
know the contingency of it the fact that
知道 它的 偶然性 的事实 ，
you know women experience what different
你知道女人有 什么不同的 经历
black people experience the world
黑人经历世界
different and you know the one way to
不同的，你知道的一种方式
explain that is reading all these
解释这 是阅读所有这些
different literature and try to find out
不同的文献，并试图找出
you you see everything so relative
你看到一切如此相对
read eBooks million years ago they
读百万年前的 电子书 他们
thought about certain problems very very
非常非常想到某些问题
differently than us today we today like
不同于我们 今天的我们今天这个样子
any culture think we know it all that's
任何文化都认为我们都知道这 一切
common to every culture every culture
每种文化都与每种文化共同
believes that at a day they know it all
相信在一天，他们知道这一切
and then you realize well there's other
然后你意识到 还有其他的
ways of viewing the universe and some of
观察宇宙的一些方法
them may have lots of things in their
他们可能会有很多东西
favor so I this is a question I wanted
所以我这是一个我想要的问题
to ask about time scale or scale in
询问的时间尺度或规模
general when you with IIT or in general
一般当你使用IIT或一般
try to think about consciousness try to
去想想意识 尝试
think about these ideas we kind of
想想这些想法 我们种
naturally think in human timescales
自然地在人类时间尺度中思考
do you or and also entities that are
你或者也是实体
sized close to humans do you think of
你想到的大小接近人类
things that are much larger much smaller
事情是更大 更小
its containing consciousness and do you
它含有意识，你呢
think of things that take you know well
想一想让你了解的事情
is this you know it ages eons to uh to
这是你知道它的年龄亿万年来 恩到
operate in their conscious cause effect
以他们有意识的因果关系运作
cause effect it's a very good question
因为这是一个非常好的问题
so I think a lot about small creatures
所以我想了很多关于 小动物 的事情
because experimentally you know a lot of
因为实验你知道很多
people work on fly then and bees alright
人们飞行 然后蜜蜂好吧
so and most people just think they are
所以大多数人都 认为 他们是
tormented a this box for heaven's sake
为了上帝的缘故折磨了这个盒子
right but if you look at their behavior
对，但如果你看看他们的行为
like bees they can recognize individual
像蜜蜂一样， 他们可以识别 个体
humans they have this very complicated
人类他们有 这么 复杂
way to communicate if you've ever been
如果你曾经去过，那 就是 沟通的 方式
involved or you know your parents when
涉及 或你了解你的父母
they bought a house what sort of
他们买了一套什么样的房子
agonizing decision that is and bees have
痛苦的决定是 蜜蜂和
to do that once a year right when they
他们每年做一次
swarm in this spring and then they have
在这个春天，然后他们有
this very lab that way they have three
这个实验室就是这样，他们 有三个
nut Scouts it did they go to the
坚果 侦察员，他们去了
individual sites they come back there
个别网站他们回到那里
this power this dance literally where
这种舞蹈的力量在哪里
they danced for several days they try to
他们试着 跳 了好几天
recruit other needs is that a
招募其他的需求是 ，
complicated decision wait when they
复杂的决定等待他们
finally want to make a decision the
最后想做出决定 了
entire swarm the scouts warm up the
整个群体的侦察员热身了
entire swarm then go to one location
整个群体然后去一个地方
they don't go to fifty location they go
他们不去五十个地方
to one location that the scouts have
到一个侦察所有的位置
agreed upon by themselves that's awesome
他们自己同意这很棒
if you look at the circuit complexity
如果你看一下电路的复杂性
it's 10 times more denser than anything
它的密度是任何东西的10倍
we have in our brain or the only of a
我们已经在我们的大脑或唯一 的
million neurons but then you know it's
百万个神经元然后你就知道了
amazing complex complex behavior very
非常复杂的复杂行为
complicated circuitry so there's no
复杂的电路，所以没有
question they experience something their
问题他们体验一番 自己的
life is very different they're tiny
生活是非常不同的，他们很小
they only live you know for four workers
他们只为 四个工人生活
live maybe for two months so I think IIT
住了两个月，所以我觉得 IIT
tells you this in principle the
原则上告诉你这个
substrate of consciousness is the
意识的基础是
substrate that maximizes the
使基质最大化的基质
cause-effect power over all possible
所有可能的因果效应
space
空间
temple grains so when I think about for
寺庙谷物所以当我想 一下
example do you know the science fiction
你知道科幻小说吗？
story the black cloud okay it's a
故事黑云 好吧，这是一个
classic by Fred Hoyle the astronomer he
天文学家弗雷德霍伊尔的经典之作
has this cloud intervening between the
这个云介于两者之间
earth and the sand the Sun and leading
土和 沙的太阳和领先
to some sort of to global cooling this
对某种形式的全球冷却
is written in the 50s it turns out you
它写于 50年代，结果证明了你
can using the the radio dish they
他们可以使用收音机
communicate was actually an entity it's
沟通实际上是一个实体
actually an intelligent entity and they
实际上是一个智能实体和他们
they sort of they convinced it to move
他们那种 他们 说服其 移动
away so here you have a radical
在这里，你有一个激进的
different entity and in principle IT
不同的实体，原则上是 IT
says well you can measure the the
说得好，你可以衡量
integrated information in principle at
原则上综合信息
least and yes if that if the maximum of
至少是，如果那是最大的
that occurs at a time scale of month
发生在 一个月 的时间尺度
rather than enough it sort of fraction
而不是足够的分数
of a second yes and they would
第二个是，他们会的
experience life where each moment is a
体验每个时刻都是生活的生活
month rather than or microsecond right
一个月而不是 微秒
rather than a fraction of a second in in
而不是一 小部分
the human case and so there may be forms
人的情况，所以可能 有形式
of constants that we simply don't
我们根本 没有的常数
recognize for what they are because they
认识到他们是什么， 因为他们
are so radically different from anything
与 任何事物 都完全 不同
you and I are used to again that's why
你和我已经习惯了这就是为什么
it's good to read or to watch science
阅读或观看 科学是件好事
fiction what we want to think about this
小说我们想要考虑什么
like this is friend you know Stanislav
像 这是朋友，你知道 斯坦尼斯拉夫
LEM this polish science fiction writer
LEM这位波兰 科幻作家
he wrote Solaris I was turned into a
他写了Solaris 我变成了一个
Hollywood movie yes
好莱坞电影是的
his best novel it was in the 60s if
他最好的小说 是在60年代，如果
there is a very ingenious and
有一个非常巧妙的
engineering background his most
工程 背景最多
interesting novel is called the
有趣的小说被称为
victorious where human civilization they
胜利的地方是人类文明
they they they they have this mission to
他们他们有这个使命
this planet and everything is destroyed
这个星球和 一切都被毁灭了
and they discover machines humans got
他们发现人类得到的机器
killed and then these machines took or
杀了然后这些机器拿了或
when there was a machine evolution a
什么时候有机器进化a
Darwinian evolution he talks about this
达尔文进化论他谈到了这一点
very vividly and finally the dominant
非常生动，最后占主导地位
they're the dominant machine
他们是主导机器
intelligence organism that survive
生存的智力生物
they're gigantic clouds of little
他们是巨大的小云
hexagonal Universal salata mater this is
这 是六角形的通用salata mater
what in the Cygnus so typically they are
什么在 天鹅座，所以他们通常是
all lying on the ground individual by
所有人都躺在地上
themselves but in times of crisis they
他们自己， 但在危机时刻他们
can't communicate the assembly into
无法将组件传达进去
gigantic Nets into clouds trillions of
巨大的篮网成云数万亿
these particles and then they become
这些粒子然后变成了
hyper intelligent and they can beat
超智能， 他们可以击败
anything that Youmans can can control at
任何 尤曼斯可以 可以 在控制
it it's a very beautiful and compelling
它是一个非常美丽和引人注目的
where you have an intelligence where
你有智慧的地方
finally the humans
最后是人类
leave the planet they simply unable to
离开他们根本无法做到的星球
understand and comprehend this creature
理解并理解这个生物
and they can say well either we can nuke
他们可以说好，我们可以核武器
the entire plan and destroy it or we
整个计划并摧毁它或我们
just have to leave because fundamentally
只是因为从根本上离开
it's an it's an alien it's so alien from
它是一个外星人，它是如此陌生
us and our ideas that we cannot
我们和我们的想法，我们不能
communicate with them
与他们沟通
yeah actually in conversation so your
是的， 实际上在谈话中，所以你的
talent US Steel or from brought up is
人才 美国钢铁公司或从中长大的是
that there could be his ideas you know
你可能知道他的想法
you already have these artificial
你已经有了这些人造的
general intelligence like super smart or
一般情报，如超级智能或
maybe conscious beings in the cellular
也许是细胞中有意识的存在
Tom so we just don't know how to talk to
汤姆，所以我们只是不知道如何交谈
them so it's the language the
他们这就是语言
communication because you don't know
沟通，因为你不知道
what to do with it so that's one sort of
该怎么做才是这样 的
view is consciousness there's only
观点是唯一的意识
something you can measure so it's not
你可以测量的东西，所以它不是
conscious if you can't measure it but so
有意识的，如果你不能测量它，但所以
you're making an ontological and an
你正在做一个本体论和一个
epistemic statement one is there they
认知论一个是他们在那里
are it's it's just like seeing their
它就像看到他们一样
multiverses that might be true but I
可能是 真的但是我 可能是 真的
can't communicate with them I don't have
我不能 与 他们 沟通
I can't have any also that's an
我不能有任何的也 这是一个
epistemic argument right so those are
认知论证是正确的，所以那些 是
two different things so may well be
很 可能是两件不同的事情
possible look at not in other case
在其他情况下可能看不到
that's happening right now people are
现在人们正在发生这种情况
building these mini organoids
建造这些迷你类器官
do you know about this so you know you
你知道 这个，所以你知道你
can take stem cells from under your arm
可以从你的手臂下取干细胞
put in one dish add four transcription
放在一个盘子里加 四个转录
factors and then you can induce them to
因素然后你可以诱导他们
code to go into large or large they're a
代码进入大或大他们是一个
few millimeters they're like a half a
几毫米他们就像一半
million neurons that look like matter of
百万个看起来像 物质的神经元
cells in a dish called mini organoids
细胞在一个叫做迷你类器官的盘子里
at Howard at Stanford everywhere they're
他们在斯坦福大学的霍华德
building them it may be well be possible
建造它们可能是可能的
that they're beginning to feel like
他们开始感觉 像
something but we we can't really
但是我们真的不能
communicate with them right now so
现在与他们沟通，使
people are beginning to think about the
人们开始 思考这个问题了
ethics of this right so yes he may be
这种权利的道德也是如此
perfectly right but they made its one
完全正确， 但他们做了一个
question are they conscious or not it's
问题是他们是否有意识
totally separate question how would I
完全独立的问题， 我 将如何
know those are two different things
知道那些是两件不同的 事情
right if you could give advice to a
对，如果你可以给一个建议
young researcher sort of dreaming of
年轻的研究员有点梦想
understanding or creating human level
理解或创造人的水平
intelligence or consciousness what would
什么会有智慧或意识
you say
你说
follow your dreams read widely no I mean
追随你的梦想 广泛阅读 我的意思
I suppose what discipline what what is
我想 什么是 什么纪律
the pursuit that they should take on is
他们应该采取的追求是
it neuroscience this is a competition
它是神经科学这是一场竞赛
cognitive science is it philosophy is a
认知科学是哲学 是一种
computer science or products
计算机科学或产品
no in in a sense that okay so the only
从某种意义上说，没有， 所以唯一的
known system that have high level of
已知的 系统 具有高水平
intelligence is Homo sapiens so if you
情报是智人，所以如果你
wanted to build it it's probably good to
想要建立它可能是好的
continue to study closely what humans do
继续 仔细 研究 人类的行为
so cognitive neuroscience you know
所以你知道认知神经科学
somewhere between cognitive neuroscience
在认知神经科学之间
on the one hand and some philosophy of
一方面和一些哲学
mind and then ai ai computer science you
记住，然后ai ai 计算机科学 你
can look at all the original ideas in
可以看看所有的原创想法
your network they all came from
你的网络都来自他们
neuroscience right reinforcement whether
神经科学正确 强化是否
it's snarky Minsky building is snarky or
这是一个讽刺的明斯基建筑是讽刺的
whether it's you know the early supalen
是不是你 知道早期的supalen
visa experiment that how about that then
签证的实验， 怎么样 ，然后
gave rise to networks and then
然后产生了网络
multi-layer networks so it may well be
多层网络，以便它可能是
possible in fact some people argue that
事实上有些人可能认为这是可能的
to make the next big step in AI once
在AI中迈出下一个重要的一步
we'll realize the limits of deep
我们将意识到 深刻 的局限
convolutional net works but they can do
卷积网络， 但他们可以做
certain things but they can't really
某些事情， 但 他们不能真的
understand but they don't they don't
明白， 但他们 不是
really can't really I can't really show
真的不能真的我真的不能表现出来
them one image I can show you a single
他们一张图片我可以给你看 一张
image of some knee a pickpocket who
一些膝盖的形象是一个扒手谁
steals a wallet from a purse you
从你的钱包里偷钱包
immediately know that's a big pocket
马上就知道这是个大口袋
right now computer system will just say
现在计算机系统就会说
well it's a man it's a woman it's a
嗯， 这是一个男人，这是一个女人，这是一个
purse right unless you train this
钱包，除非你训练这个
machine on showing it a hundred thousand
机器上显示它十万
pickpockets right so it doesn't it
扒手右所以它不会吧
doesn't have this easy understanding
没有这么容易理解
that you have right so so some people
你有权 这么一些 人
make yeah I mean in order to go to the
使是的， 我的意思是为了去
next step or you really want to build
下一步还是你真的想要建立
machines that understand in a way you
以某种方式理解你的机器
and I we have to go to psychology we
而我，我们必须去心理学
need to understand how we do it and our
我需要了解我们是如何做到这一点的
brains enable us to do it and so
大脑使我们能够做到这一点
therefore being on the cusp it's also so
因此，处于风口浪尖也是如此
exciting I'd to try to understand better
令人兴奋的是我想要 更好 地理解
our nature and then to build to take
我们的本性，然后建立采取
some of those inside and build them so I
其中一些内部并构建它们所以 我
think the most exciting thing is
认为最令人兴奋 的是
somewhere in the interface between
介于两者之间的界面
cognitive science neuroscience AI
认知科学神经科学 AI
computer science and philosophy of mind
计算机科学和心灵哲学
beautiful yeah I'd say if there is from
美丽是啊我会说，如果有来自
the machine learning for from the
机器 从中 学习
computer science computer vision
计算机科学计算机视觉
perspective many of the researchers kind
透视许多 研究人员的 善意
of ignore the way the human brain works
无视人类大脑的运作方式
nor even psychology or literature or
甚至 也不 是心理或文献或
studying the brain I would hope Josh
研究大脑我希望乔希
Tenenbaum talks about bringing that in
Tenenbaum谈到将其纳入其中
more and more and that's yeah so you've
越来越多，那就是 你所以
worked on some amazing stuff throughout
在整个过程中都有一些令人惊奇
your life what's the thing that you're
你的生活有什么是你的事
really excited about what's the mystery
什么是神秘感 真的很兴奋
that you would love to uncover in the
你会喜欢 发现的
near term beyond
近期
beyond all the mysteries already
已经超越了所有的奥秘
surrounded by well so there's a
被井包围所以有一个
structure called the Klaus poem
结构称为克劳斯诗
this is structures underneath our cortex
这是我们皮层下面的结构
it's yay big you have one on the left am
这是耶大，你有一个左上午
i right underneath this pie underneath a
我 正下方这个馅饼下方 的
insula it's very sane it's like one
insula它非常合理，就像一个
millimeter it's embedded in in wiring in
毫米它嵌入在布线中
white matters it's very difficult to
白色问题 非常困难
image and it has it has connection to
图像，它有它的连接
every cortical region and Francis Crick
每个皮层区域和弗朗西斯 克里克
the last paper you have of all he
你最后一篇论文是他的全部
dictated Corrections the day he died in
口述更正他死的那天
hospital on this paper
医院在这篇论文上
he now we hyper hypothesize well because
他现在我们假设得很好， 因为
it has this unique Anatomy it gets input
它有这种独特的解剖学输入
from every cortical area and projects
来自每个皮层区域和项目
back to every call every cortical area
回到每个皮质区域的每个呼叫
that the function of this structure is
这个结构的功能是
similar that it's just a metaphor to
类似的 ，它只是一个比喻 来
work the role of a conducting and
发挥指挥的作用
symphony orchestra
交响乐 队
you've all the different cortical
你有 各种 不同的皮质
players you have some that do motion
玩家你有一些动作
some they do theory of mind some that
有些他们做了一些心理理论
infer social interaction and color I'm
推断我的社交互动和色彩
hearing and all the different modules
听证会和所有不同的模块
and cortex but of course what
和皮质，但当然是什么
consciousness is consciousness puts it
意识就是意识所说的
all together into one package like the
所有人一起组成一个 像
binding problem all of that and this is
绑定问题所有 这 一切 ，这是
really the function because it has a
真的 是功能，因为它有一个
relatively few nuance compared to cortex
与皮质相比，相对较少的细微差别
but it it talks it is all receive the
但它说它是全部收到的
input from all of them and it projects
来自所有人的投入和项目
back to all of them and so we are
回到他们所有人，所以我们是
testing that right now we've got this
现在我们测试了这个
beautiful neuronal reconstruction in the
在美丽的神经元重建
mouse called crown of song and town of
老鼠叫歌冠和 镇
Thal nuan said there in the closed room
Thal nuan说在封闭的房间里
that if the most widespread connection
如果最广泛的连接
of any nerve Neon I've ever seen they're
任何神经 霓虹我见过他们
very deep yeah you have individually on
很深， 是的， 你 个别地
to sit in the clouds from tiny but then
从小而 坐在 云端
they have this very single you have this
他们有这个单身你有这个
huge axonal tree that cover both FC and
巨大的轴突树，覆盖FC和
contralateral cortex and and trying to
对侧皮质并试图
turn using you know fancy tools like
转而使用你知道像花哨的工具
optogenetics trying to turn those
光遗传学试图扭转这些局面
neurons on or off and study it what
神经元开启或关闭并研究它是什么
happens in them in the mouse so this
在鼠标中发生这样的事情
thing is perhaps where the parts become
可能是零件成为的地方
the whole it very interface it's one of
整个它 非常 接口它是其中之一
the structures it's a very good way of
结构是一种非常好的方式
putting it where the the individual
把它放在个人的地方
parts turn into the whole of the whole
零件变成了整体
of the conscious experience well with
有意识的体验
that thank you very much for being here
非常感谢你来到这里
today thank you jack thank you much
今天谢谢 插孔谢谢你多少
you
您